FÁBIO SOUSA

CONTACTS



(+351) 964233838



fabiodaniel.2000@gmail.com



Portfolio



<u>Linktree</u>

ABOUT ME

Recent graduate with a Master's degree in Telecommunications and Informatics Engineering. I have been designing games since middle school, mostly in paper, and started programming in highschool some of them. In university I have worked on bigger and more polished games, making them with other people and publishing them online. I love the star wars franchise and my favourite food is cheesecake.

TECH STACK

- C#
- Python
- C
- C++
- Java
- Android Studio
- AWS

- Unity
- Godot
- Unreal
- Mirror Networking
- Photon Engine
- PyGame

LANGUAGES

Portuguese - Native English - C2

EXPERIENCE

President | Game Developer

GameDev Ténico | 2020 - Now

- Game Development Student Association.
- Game Programmer and Game Designer for 2D, 3D and online multiplayer games.
- Published 1 mobile game that is being used in Portuguese Public Schools as a teaching tool on Sustainability.
- Raised more than 40.000€ to fund all the projects over 3 years.
- Contributed to an Open Source Voxel Engine in C++.

Member | Web Developer

<u>IEEE-IST</u> | 2018 - 2020

- Developed and published a website using Python Framworks (Django and Flask).
- Wrote tutorials on how to develop robots using Raspberry Pi Computers.

EDUCATION

Instituto Superior Técnico University of Lisbon



MSE IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS AND INFORMATICS ENGINEERING 2021 - 2023

Finished my master's degree in one of the best engineering university in Portugal. Focused my studies on Distributed Systems and Deep Learning and side courses in Game Design and Game Development.

BSE IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS AND INFORMATICS ENGINEERING 2018 - 2021

Concluded my bachelor's degree while participating in several extra curricular activities and voluntary work.

AWARDS

Best Game Award

GGJ 2023 @ Técnico/Belas-Artes

Developed a Chaotic Multiplayer Puzzle Game which was reviewed and awarded with Best Game Award by Funcom Representatives.

Best Game and Design Award

Breaking Dev 2019

Developed a Top Down Shooter which was reviewed and awarded with Best Game Award and Best Design Award by industry professionals.

ASSOCIATIONS

Vice President | Events Team NEETI | 2019 - 2023

- Course's Student Group
- Tutored 1st years students for programming courses.
- Organized workshops in a variety of topics.

Member | Partnerships Team SET | 2018 - 2020

- Business and Technological Week
- Contacted Companies and Speakers to participate in this event and network with university students.

Member | Events Team

LAGE2 | 2018 - 2019

- Student Group focused on organising extra-curricular events.
- Organized Board Game Tournaments.

Volunteer | Logistics Team

Lisboa Games Week | 2018 - 2020

- Biggest Videogame Event in Portugal.
- Visitor information support.
- Support in the auditoriums, activities and workshops

PROJECTS

MIX N' SMASH

A fast paced puzzle game where the player has to, you guessed it, mix and smash geometric figures in order to achieve the goal of each level

This game was made for a 1 week Game Jam in May 2023 and has been in constant development since.

For this game I was the Game Designer and one of the Game Programmers.

Showcased this game at <u>Indie Dev Days</u> in Barcelona, Spain, September 2023

STAR LOOP

A one button puzzle game where the player controls a spaceship throughout the vastness of the universe using wormholes.

This game was made for a 48 hour Game Jam in April 2022, the <u>Nordic Game Jam</u> in Copenhagen, Denmark.

For this game I was the Game Designer and one of the Game Programmers.

Showcased this game at <u>Lisboa Games Week</u> in Lisbon, Portugal, November 2022

SMASHCART ULTRA

Smashcart Ultra is a 3D online multiplayer party game where you take control of a crazy shopping cart through several shopping centers in different and fun mini-games!

This game was made as a submission for <u>FNAC</u> <u>Novos Talentos</u> in 2020 and <u>Playstation Talents</u> in 2021.

For this game I was the Network Programmer. Showcased this game at <u>International Science</u> <u>Festival in Oeiras</u>, Portugal, October 2021.

ELMO - THESIS

Programmed a social robot for the master's thesis that would play a card game with deaf children. The game is played online and multiplayer, being played mostly on tablets.